

Berkeley, California

□ 510-388-2095 | ■ daancamps@gmail.com | ★ campsd.github.io | • campsd | • campsd

Summary_

Computational mathematics postdoctoral researcher at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory with a broad scientific interest and a passion for problem-solving. Close to 2 years research experience in quantum information and quantum algorithms, 6+ years experience in computational mathematics, and 2+ years experience as project engineer.

Work Experience_

Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory

Berkeley, USA

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER IN COMPUTATIONAL MATHEMATICS

Nov. 2019 - Current

- · Research project on quantum information and quantum algorithms with a focus on circuit compilation and synthesis.
- Worked on a variety of problems ranging from Hamiltonian simulation to quantum linear algebra.
- Developed QCLAB, QCLAB++, F3C and F3C++.
- · Team scientist.

KU Leuven Leuven, Belgium

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019 TEACHING ASSISTANT

- · Guided exercise sessions for courses on numerical modeling and approximation, numerical mathematics.
- · Mentor of two master student projects.

IPCOS NV Leuven, Belgium

PROJECT ENGINEER IN DIGITAL OILFIELD TEAM

Aug. 2013 - Sep. 2015

- · Deployment and maintenance of upstream production monitoring models based on real-time process data.
- Development and deployment of new data-driven pipeline leak detection models.
- · Customer-oriented role: presenting on-site training sessions and providing end user support.

Education _____

KU Leuven (University of Leuven)

Leuven, Belgium

PhD in Computer Science and Applied Mathematics

Sep. 2015 - Sep. 2019

- Thesis: 'Pole swapping methods for the eigenvalue problem Rational QR algorithms'.
- Research in numerical linear algebra with a strong focus on eigenvalue problems.

KU Leuven (University of Leuven)

Leuven, Belgium

M.Sc.Eng. in Mathematical Engineering

Sep. 2011 - Jun. 2013

• Thesis: 'Epileptic seizure monitoring using tensor decomposition techniques'.

KU Leuven (University of Leuven)

Leuven, Belgium

M.Sc. in Astronomy and Astrophysics

Sep. 2009 - Sep. 2011

• Thesis: 'Heschel/PACS observations of water in the carbon-rich AGB star V Hya'.

UHasselt (University of Hasselt)

Hasselt, Belgium

B SC IN PHYSICS

Sep. 2006 - Jun. 2010

Skills, Competencies & Training

Programming

Matlab, Python, Fortran, C++.

Opensource projects

- QCLAB and QCLAB++ software packages for quantum circuit development, analysis and simulation.
- Fast free fermion compiler F3C and F3C++ for fast and scalable quantum circuit compilation for Hamiltonian simulation. Quantum algorithms, Quantum circuit synthesis, Numerical linear algebra, Eigenvalue problems, Tensor decomposition

Research interests

techniques, Computational mathematics. · Mathematics of Big Data: Sketching and (Multi-)Linear Algebra (MSRI Graduate Summer School, 2021)

Formal training

- OpenMPI (ICTS, 2018)
- Fundamentals of Machine Learning (SOCN Graduate School, 2018)
- Low-Rank Tensor Techniques (Haussdorff School, 2016)

510-388-2095 DAAN CAMPS · CV

Language Skills

Dutch Native English Fluent **French** Moderate

Preprints & Publications

	2021	$\textbf{An Algebraic Quantum Circuit Compression Algorithm for Hamiltonian Simulation}, \texttt{Camps D.}, \texttt{K\"{o}kc\"{u}E.},$
		Bassman L., de Jong W.A., Kemper A.F., Van Beeumen R. arXiv:2108.03283.
	2021	Algebraic Compression of Quantum Circuits for Hamiltonian Evolution , Kökcü E., Camps D., Bassman L.,
		Freericks J.K., de Jong W.A., Van Beeumen R., Kemper A.F. arXiv:2108.03282.
	2021	A Multishift, Multipole Rational QZ Method with Aggressive Early Deflation, Steel T., Camps D.,
		Meerbergen K., Vandebril R., SIAM J. Matrix Anal. Appl. 42(2), 753–774. DOI: 10.1137/19M1249631
	2020	Approximate Quantum Circuit Synthesis using Block Encodings, Camps D., Van Beeumen R., Phys. Rev. A
		102, 052411. DOI: 10.1103/PhysRevA.102.052411
	2020	Chemistry on Quantum Computers with Virtual Quantum Subspace Expansion , Urbanek M., Camps D.,
	2020	Van Beeumen R., de Jong W. A., J. Chem. Theory Comput. 16(9), 5425–5431. DOI: 10.1021/acs.jctc.0c00447
	2020	Quantum Fourier Transform Revisited , Camps D., Van Beeumen R., Yang C., Numer. Linear Algebra Appl.
	2020	28(1). DOI: 10.1002/nla.2331
	2020	On Pole-Swapping Algorithms for the Eigenvalue Problem, Camps D., Mach T., Vandebril R., Watkins D.
		S., Electron. Trans. Numer. Anal. 52, 480–508. DOI: 10.1553/etna_vol52s480
	2019	Swapping 2x2 blocks in the Schur and generalized Schur form, Camps D., Mastronardi N., Vandebril R.,
		Van Dooren P., J. Comput. Appl. Math. 373. 112274. DOI: 10.1016/j.cam.2019.05.022
	2019	A rational QZ method, Camps D., Meerbergen K., Vandebril R., SIAM J. Matrix Anal. Appl. 40(3), 943–972.
		DOI: 10.1137/18M1170480
	2019	An implicit filter for rational Krylov using core transformations, Camps D., Meerbergen K., Vandebril R.,
		Linear Algebra and its Applications, DOI: 10.1016/j.laa.2018.09.021
		Block term decomposition for modelling epileptic seizures, Hunyadi B., Camps D., Sorber L., Van

Talks_

APS March Meeting	Virtual	l confe	erence	9
-------------------	---------	---------	--------	---

Paesschen W., De Vos M., Van Huffel S., De Lathauwer L., EURASIP Journal on Advances in Signal Processing,

APPROXIMATE QUANTUM CIRCUIT SYNTHESIS USING BLOCK ENCODINGS

DOI: 10.1186/1687-6180-2014-139

SIAM Conference on Computational Science and Engineering

Understanding the quantum Fourier transform through matrix decompositions

CS Area 2nd Annual Postdoc Symposium

APPROXIMATE QUANTUM CIRCUIT SYNTHESIS USING BLOCK ENCODINGS

Berkeley Lab Seminar

POLE SWAPPING METHODS FOR THE EIGENVALUE PROBLEM – RATIONAL QR ALGORITHMS

ICIAM Conference

POLE SWAPPING METHODS FOR THE EIGENVALUE PROBLEM – RATIONAL QR ALGORITHMS

ETNA25 Conference

APPROXIMATE INVERSE-FREE RATIONAL KRYLOV METHODS AND THE LINK WITH FOM AND GMRES

A RATIONAL QZ METHOD SIAM Conference on Applied Linear Algebra

ROZ: A RATIONAL OZ METHOD FOR THE GENERALIZED EIGENVALUE PROBLEM

NUMA Internal Seminar

RATIONAL MATRIX ALGORITHMS FOR THE GENERALIZED EIGENVALUE PROBLEM — ITERATIVE AND DIRECT METHODS

Numerical Analysis and Scientific Computation with Applications (NASCA) Conference

Mar. 2021

Virtual conference

Mar. 2021

Berkeley, USA

Feb. 2021

Berkeley, USA

Sep. 2019

Valencia, Spain

Jul. 2019

Santa Margherita di Pula, Italy

May 2019

Kalamata, Greece

Jul. 2018

Hong Kong

May. 2018

Leuven, Belgium

Oct. 2017

Conference of the International Linear Algebra Society (ILAS)

Iowa, USA

On the implicit restart of the rational Krylov method — Chasing algorithms for polynomial, extended and rational Krylov

Jul. 2017

Jul. 2016

Conference of the International Linear Algebra Society (ILAS)

Leuven, Belgium

TOWARDS A COMPUTATIONAL EFFICIENT, IMPLICITLY RESTARTED RATIONAL KRYLOV METHOD